A Guide to the Ruiz Case Office of Special Master Records, 1979-1992.
Ruiz Case Office of Special Master Records,
- Lufkin Division: (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Ronnie Roland (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Thomas vs. Thaler, et. al. (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Roach vs. McKaskle (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Nunley vs. Wood (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Calhoun vs. Jackson (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Woodward vs. McKaskle (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Briggs vs. McKaskle (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Young vs. Maple (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Brown vs. Estelle, et. al. (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Glenn vs. Hanson and Maples (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Young vs. McKaskle (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Smith vs. McKaskle (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Woodson vs. Adams (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Woodson vs. Ramirez (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Woodson vs. Craig (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Carr vs. Flasowski (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Black, Jerry L. (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Dennis vs. McKaskle, et. al. (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Glenn vs. Hirschfelder (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Dean vs. McKaskle (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Williams vs. Simmons (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Williams vs. Thaler (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Wallace vs. McKaskle (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Johnson vs. McKaskle (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Jackson vs. McKaskle (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Gray vs. McKaskle (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Wallis vs. Stephens (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Jackson vs. Myers (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Garacci vs. Gilmore (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Garacci vs. McKaskle (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Leach vs. McKaskle (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Rodden vs. McKaskle (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Jones vs. McKaskle (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Carter vs. Thaler, et. al. (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Harris, Tommie Melvin (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Ervin Kingsbury (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Garacci, Anthony (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
  - Mann vs. Procunier (Box 94-485/42 (05268113))
- TDC reports, major structural deficiences: (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - Beto Units 1-2 (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - Central Unit (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - Clements Unit (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - Coffield Unit (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - Darrington Unit (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - Diagnostic Unit (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - Eastham Unit (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - Ellis Units 1-2 (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - Ferguson Unit (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - Gatesville Unit (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - Goree Unit (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - Hilltop Unit (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - Huntsville Unit (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - Jester Units 1-3 (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - Mt. View Unit (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - Pack Units 1-2 (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - Ramsey Units 1-3 (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - Retrieve Unit (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - Wynne Unit (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
- Quarterly compliance report: (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - 1st, February 1983 (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - 2nd, April 1983 (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - 4th, October 1983 (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - 5th, January 1984 (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - 6th, April 1984 (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - 7th, July 1984 (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - 8th, October 1984 (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - 9th, January 1985 (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - 10th, April 1985 (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - 11th, July 1985 (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - 12th, October 1985 (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - 13th, December 1985 (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
  - 14th, March 1986 (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
- Texas classification plan, 1983-1984 (Box 94-485/43 (05274932))
- Staffing study of the units of the TDC, final report, September 10, 1982 (Box 94-458/44 (05268215))
- TDC staffing study, September 10, 1982 (Box 94-458/44 (05268215))
- 26th staff counsel institute (Box 94-458/44 (05268215))
- 27th Support Service Institute (Box 94-458/44 (05268215))
- Solitary confinement (Box 94-458/44 (05268215))
- McCotter vs. Ruiz (Box 94-458/44 (05268215))
- Use of Force (Box 94-458/44 (05268215))
- TDCs amended use of force plan, April 29, 1985 (Box 94-458/44 (05268215))
- Use of force (Box 94-458/44 (05268215))
- Use of force plans (Box 94-458/44 (05268215))
- TDC revised health care plan, December 1981 (Box 94-458/45 (05274660))
- TDC revised health care plan, 3 Vols., November 1992 (Box 94-458/45 (05274660))
- Appendices to 6th monitors report (Box 94-458/45 (05274660))
- 28th monitors report, report on section IV.C of the amended decree, administrative segregation (Box 94-458/45 (05274660))
- Report on the 28th monitors report (Box 94-458/45 (05274660))
- TDC classification, 1984 (Box 94-458/45 (05274660))
- 33rd monitors report, report concerning implementation of classification plan (Box 94-458/45 (05274660))
- Quarterly compliance reports: (Box 94-458/45 (05274660))
  - 5th, September 1986 (Box 94-458/45 (05274660))
  - 6th, December 1986 (Box 94-458/45 (05274660))
  - 7th, September 1986 (Box 94-458/45 (05274660))
  - 17th, December 1986 (Box 94-458/45 (05274660))
- Report of the 33rd report (Box 94-458/45 (05274660))
- Report concerning 22nd monitors report (Box 94-458/45 (05274660))
- 22nd monitors report, report on stipulation and order modifying courts order of January 11, 1984 (out of cell program at Coffield and Ellis I), 2 Vols. (Box 94-458/45 (05274660))
- Summary of execution procedures in Texas (Box 94-458/45 (05274660))
- Semi-annual progress report on TDCs comprehensive health care plan, psychiatric services plan, mentally retarded offender plan, physically handicapped, October 1985 - March 1986 and April-September, 1986 (Box 94-458/45 (05274660))
- Second tri-annual progress report, TDCs comprehensive health care plan (Box 94-458/45 (05274660))
- 28th monitors report (Box 94-458/45 (05274660))
- Appendices to health care report, October 1985 (Box 94-458/45 (05274660))
- Report on the defendants' psychiatric services plan, comprehensive services plan and the stipulation on solitary confinement health precautions, October 1985 (Box 94-458/45 (05274660))
- TDC discipline rules, classification plan and grievance proceudres memo (Box 94-458/45 (05274660))
- Proposed agenda, comprehensive health care plan (Box 94-458/45 (05274660))
- Death row (Box 94-458/45 (05274660))
- Record of proceedings, oral hearing on show cause order, Vols. I-III (Box 94-458/46 (05268146))
- Civil docket continuation sheets (Box 94-458/46 (05268146))
- 7th quarterly compliance report, stipulation modifying crowding provisions of amended decree (Box 94-458/46 (05268146))
- Supplemental plan for the physically handicapped offender program, March 27, 1987 (Box 94-458/46 (05268146))
- TDC recreational facilities assessment, April 6, 1987 (Box 94-458/46 (05268146))
- TDC recreational facilities assessment, appendix (Box 94-458/46 (05268146))
- 13th monitors report to the Special Master concerning the state of the defendants' compliance with the stipulation modifying crowding provisions of amended decree (Box 94-458/47 (05268124))
- Report of the Special Master concerning 13th report (Box 94-458/47 (05268124))
- 27th monitors report, defendants' compliance at eight TDC units with the support service, inmate provisions (Box 94-458/47 (05268124))
- Special Master's report on 27th report (Box 94-458/47 (05268124))
- Report of the Special Master concerning the 2nd addendum to the 24th monitors report (Box 94-458/47 (05268124))
- 2nd addendum to the 24th monitors report (Box 94-458/47 (05268124))
- 23rd Special Master's report, defendants' complaince, overcrowding (Box 94-458/47 (05268124))
- 21st monitors report (Box 94-458/47 (05268124))
- Report of the Special Master concerning the 21st monitors report (Box 94-458/47 (05268124))
- 29th monitors report, use of force draft (Box 94-458/47 (05268124))
- 19th monitors report, II.C. of amended decree, use of force (Box 94-458/47 (05268124))
- 18th monitors' reported report of the Special Master concerning 18th monitors' report (Box 94-458/47 (05268124))
- Report of the Special Master and 10th monitors report, support and service inmates, I-III (Box 94-458/47 (05268124))
- Overcrowding (Box 94-458/48 (05268168))
- TDC monitoring housing reports (Box 94-458/48 (05268168))
- TDC new construction reports (Box 94-458/48 (05268168))
- TDC, answer to the Gordon report, New Construction Division (Box 94-458/48 (05268168))
- Staffing (Box 94-458/48 (05268168))